<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Devops Gathering 2020 | March 09 - 11, 2020 in Bochum</title>
    <link>https://devops-gathering.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Devops Gathering 2020 | March 09 - 11, 2020 in Bochum</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 30 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://devops-gathering.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Cloud Native Ecosystem 101</title>
      <link>https://devops-gathering.io/talks/cloud-native-ecosystem-101/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://devops-gathering.io/talks/cloud-native-ecosystem-101/</guid>
      <description>Cloud native computing allows teams to build and manage services using container architectures and stringing them together into applications, without worrying about servers at all. The ecosystem is growing fast and a lot of changes are ahead. The combination of cloud services and kubernetes as a platform are the way to go. This talk give you technical overview of currently available cloud native ecosystem and future of container based systems.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Going Serverless</title>
      <link>https://devops-gathering.io/workshops/going-serverless/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://devops-gathering.io/workshops/going-serverless/</guid>
      <description>Everybody&amp;rsquo;s hyped about Serverless, but what is it exactly about and what does it mean to develop a real application with it? Instead of just writing a simple &amp;ldquo;hello world function&amp;rdquo; in this workshop, we&amp;rsquo;re going to create a real weather application using different AWS buildings blocks. While building a scalable and cheap weather application, we&amp;rsquo;ll also look into the tricks and challenges of Lambda, DynamoDB, SQS, XRay and Cloudwatch. At the end of this workshop, you&amp;rsquo;ll have the tools and skills to develop your own Serverless app.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kubernetes 101</title>
      <link>https://devops-gathering.io/workshops/kubernetes-101/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://devops-gathering.io/workshops/kubernetes-101/</guid>
      <description>This Workshop will explain the basic concepts of Kubernetes. Questions like How can I expose my Kubernetes App to the world or How can I run my Container in Kubernetes ? Also it will deliver a Higher Overview over Kubernetes Architecture and the basic components.
Prerequisite knowledge  A working knowledge of the Linux command line A basic understanding of containers and container runtimes like Docker A basic understanding of microservices  What you&amp;rsquo;ll learn During this workshop you will learn the basics components of Kubernetes and get an overview of the current Architecture of Kubernetes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The first decade of DevOps is over!</title>
      <link>https://devops-gathering.io/talks/the-first-decade-of-devops-is-over/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://devops-gathering.io/talks/the-first-decade-of-devops-is-over/</guid>
      <description>The DevOps movement started 2009 at a small conference in Ghent. I’ll take you on a journey through ten years of DevOps and try to show how the topic has evolved since that time. In the beginning DevOps was an experiment to improve the collaboration just between Dev and Ops people. Today DevOps is often seen as tooling, as many tremendous changes in IT happened since then: the rise of container technology, Microservices, Public Cloud Services, Serverless and Infrastructure as Code - just to name a few of them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ansible: Testing with Molecule</title>
      <link>https://devops-gathering.io/workshops/ansible-testing-with-molecule/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://devops-gathering.io/workshops/ansible-testing-with-molecule/</guid>
      <description>This workshop gives an introduction on test-driven development of ansible roles with molecule ( https://molecule.readthedocs.io/en/stable )
Molecule provides support for testing with multiple instances, operating systems and distributions, virtualization providers, test frameworks and testing scenarios.
This workshop is hands-on and is designed for molecule beginner, basic ansible knowledge about playbook and role development is required.
Small parts will be implemented in Python, but should be understandable to every developer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>From Containers to Kubernetes Operators</title>
      <link>https://devops-gathering.io/talks/from-containers-to-kubernetes-operators/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://devops-gathering.io/talks/from-containers-to-kubernetes-operators/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;Containers are the new ZIP format to distribute software&amp;rdquo; is a fitting description of today&amp;rsquo;s development world. However, it is not always that easy and this talk highlights the development of Elastic&amp;rsquo;s container strategy over time: Docker images, Docker Compose, Helm Charts, and a Kubernetes Operator.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building a Graph User-Interface for Malware-Analysis</title>
      <link>https://devops-gathering.io/talks/building-graph-ui-for-malware-analysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://devops-gathering.io/talks/building-graph-ui-for-malware-analysis/</guid>
      <description>As a security company, G DATA built a large JanusGraph database with information about different malware threats over the years. This talk shows how we built an interactive graph interface to explore the data using auto-generated GraphQL interfaces and open-source JavaScript libraries for graph rendering.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introduction to Kubernetes Operators</title>
      <link>https://devops-gathering.io/workshops/introduction-to-kubernetes-operators/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://devops-gathering.io/workshops/introduction-to-kubernetes-operators/</guid>
      <description>Operators are a powerful tool to unlock automation and management potential in clusters. In this workshop I will first introduce and explain some core concepts of Kubernetes operators such as the controller pattern, eventual consistency, custom resources and status management in Kubernetes. The next phase in the workshop will be creating and running your first operator using the Kubebuilder SDK (https://github.com/kubernetes-sigs/kubebuilder) and utilizing KIND (https://github.com/kubernetes-sigs/kind) to deploy your operator locally.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Serverless Azure Functions in the Azure Cloud</title>
      <link>https://devops-gathering.io/talks/serverless-functions-in-azure-cloud/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://devops-gathering.io/talks/serverless-functions-in-azure-cloud/</guid>
      <description>Ten years ago, Azure started with a strong focus on PaaS. No wonder that Serverless has also become super important in Microsoft’s cloud recently. Rainer Stropek has been using Azure since the days of the first technical previews. In this session, Rainer will introduce you to Azure Functions, one of the Serverless offerings in Azure. Instead of speaking about theory, Rainer will walk you through an end-to-end sample and use it to describe the inner workings of Azure Function’s programming model.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>From Zero to Hero - Onboarding with GitOps</title>
      <link>https://devops-gathering.io/talks/onboarding-with-git-ops/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://devops-gathering.io/talks/onboarding-with-git-ops/</guid>
      <description>In 2019 our container count raised by more than 1000 containers and together with the development department we are running more than 45.000 CI/CD jobs with GitLab on-premises per month now. During this hot time of growth one colleague quit his job and we have to find and onboard a new young colleague. With all hands on deck, we managed it surprising easily not only to onboard the new colleague within a couple of weeks, we onboard a developer to our team in parallel too!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Amazon EKS Workshop</title>
      <link>https://devops-gathering.io/workshops/amazon-eks-workshop/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://devops-gathering.io/workshops/amazon-eks-workshop/</guid>
      <description>Running more than one containerized application in production makes teams look for solutions to quickly deploy and orchestrate containers. One of the most popular options is the open-source project Kubernetes. With the release of the Amazon Elastic Container Service for Kubernetes (EKS), engineering teams now have access to a fully managed Kubernetes control plane and time to focus on building applications. With AWS Fargate, you don’t need to be an expert in Kubernetes operations to run a cost-optimized and highly-available cluster.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Routing Your Microservices Architecture to Ease DevOps Enterprise Transformation</title>
      <link>https://devops-gathering.io/talks/routing-your-microservices-architecture-to-ease-devops-enterprise-transformation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://devops-gathering.io/talks/routing-your-microservices-architecture-to-ease-devops-enterprise-transformation/</guid>
      <description>In a world of containerized microservices, where developers focus on building and exposing applications to end users as fast as possible, adapting the enterprise to this new pace of change poses significant challenges. Routing requests to your microservices, either coming from end users or other microservices, is one of them. It’s never been easier to have Canary routing, so you can “verify” that a new features of your application works in production by testing it on a small subset of users.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to provide reliable Postgres Database inside of Kubernetes Cluster with a Postgres Operator</title>
      <link>https://devops-gathering.io/workshops/reliable-postgres-operator/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://devops-gathering.io/workshops/reliable-postgres-operator/</guid>
      <description>We will show the workings of the Zalando Postgres Operator inside of Kubernetes. We will elaborate on the do and don&amp;rsquo;t of using the Operator. Practical examples how to control Data Placement and Backup will conclude the Workshop. As a bonus we will install an graphile api generator on top of Postgres. graphile automatically generates a graphql api from an Postgres schema and provides a &amp;ldquo;nocode&amp;rdquo; backend for simple Web and Mobile applications.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Let&#39;s Go Knative</title>
      <link>https://devops-gathering.io/talks/lets-go-knative/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://devops-gathering.io/talks/lets-go-knative/</guid>
      <description>Are you tired of the complexity of your building applications with Kubernetes? You need to add your own resources like deployment, service, ingress, config maps, secrets and many more to run your applications in Kubernetes. Knative attempts to solve theses complexities by managing its servicing and lifecycle while providing ‘serverless’ style event-driven functions. In this talk I’ll give you a first hands-on look to Knative with the components Serving, Eventing and it’s underlying components.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Serverless Workloads with Knative</title>
      <link>https://devops-gathering.io/talks/serverless-workloads-with-knative/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://devops-gathering.io/talks/serverless-workloads-with-knative/</guid>
      <description>Knative is a Kubernetes-based platform that comes with a set of building blocks to deploy and manage modern serverless workloads. Knative consists of two main components: Serving and Eventing. The session gives you an introduction into the Knative Serving and Eventing components and walks you through several demos with a focus on Knative serving. We will also get to know the brand new CLI client &amp;ldquo;kn&amp;rdquo; which allows interacting with Knative without writing a single line of YAML.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Infrastructure as Microservices - Alternatives to the Monolithic Kubernetes</title>
      <link>https://devops-gathering.io/talks/infrastructure-as-microservices/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://devops-gathering.io/talks/infrastructure-as-microservices/</guid>
      <description>It is en Vogue to subdivide applications into professionally cut microservices and operate them in Kubernetes clusters. Strictly speaking, a Kubernet cluster is a monolithic system consisting of inseparable services. This means that the individual services cannot be operated or switched off independently of each other. This concept is strongly reminiscent of the 90&amp;rsquo;s with their large application servers. It would be logical to adapt the operating concept to the software architecture: Offer independently operable infrastructure services, such as service registry, deployment distribution, load balancing&amp;hellip; In this lecture, we would like to show how the microservice concept of small, closed, specialized modules can also be implemented in infrastructure services without Kubernetes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Knative Eventing: Deep Dive</title>
      <link>https://devops-gathering.io/talks/knative-eventing-deep-dive/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://devops-gathering.io/talks/knative-eventing-deep-dive/</guid>
      <description>Knative is a Kubernetes-based platform that comes with a set of building blocks to build, deploy, and manage modern serverless workloads. The Eventing component covers the aspect to manage the lifecycle of event-driven applications. This session gives you a deep dive into Knative Eventing and showing various parts, and the integration of Apache Kafka for effcient event delivery. The session is supported by an end-to-end demo, to manifest the learned concepts of Knative Eventing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Testing with Containers</title>
      <link>https://devops-gathering.io/workshops/testing-with-containers/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://devops-gathering.io/workshops/testing-with-containers/</guid>
      <description>Enterprise projects and the resulting challenges are complex by definition. How to master such a system and realize short &amp;ldquo;time-to-market&amp;rdquo; cycles at the same time without negotiating regression errors? The answer is as easy as simple - extensive automated test suites which continuously accumulate the errors back flow. But how to setup these tests when dealing with numerous services, databases, message brokers and other infrastructure to be integrated. At this point Docker comes into the game, which enables us to run an production-near setup in the developer machine as well as in multiple staging environments.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lightning Talks</title>
      <link>https://devops-gathering.io/talks/lightning-talks/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://devops-gathering.io/talks/lightning-talks/</guid>
      <description>Robert Douglass: Develop and deploy on containers with just a few lines of YAML, no Docker, and no Kubernetes
Many organizations are investing big on learning new technologies because of the clear benefits that they offer. What if you could have those same benefits, and work a lot less getting them? Platform.sh is a Platform-as-a-Service that lets web application developers benefit from a fully containerized continuous deployment workflow without having to learn Docker or Kubernetes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Software Factory - Why technology is not enough</title>
      <link>https://devops-gathering.io/talks/the-software-factory-why-technology-is-not-enough/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://devops-gathering.io/talks/the-software-factory-why-technology-is-not-enough/</guid>
      <description>Continuous Integration, Delivery and Deployment has become to a success factor for agile software companies all over the world. To be able to deliver software multiple times a day and not only once or twice a year had massive impact to their business and a role model for dev and ops teams which began to establish efficient and fast running software assembly lines and flexible production environments. But the even the best technology will not lead to minimal release cycles if the rest of your company is still stuck in old fashioned ways of planing projects, wirting requirements and modelling architectures.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introduction to Go</title>
      <link>https://devops-gathering.io/workshops/introduction-to-go/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://devops-gathering.io/workshops/introduction-to-go/</guid>
      <description>Go has become a popular programming language. Particularly in the DevOps space, Go has risen in popularity because Docker, Kubernetes &amp;amp; Co are written in this programming language. The strengths of Go are beside others simplicity, consistency, good support for async and parallel programming and efficiency. That makes the language a perfect match for Microservices- and DevOps-projects. This workshop is for DevOps engineers who are curious about what Go is. You don&amp;rsquo;t need to have Go experience for this workshop.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Testcontainers - a Year-in-review</title>
      <link>https://devops-gathering.io/talks/testcontainers-a-year-in-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://devops-gathering.io/talks/testcontainers-a-year-in-review/</guid>
      <description>Unit testing is fine, but without proper integration testing, especially if you work with external resources like databases and other services, you might not know how your application will actually behave once it has been deployed to the real production environment. Testcontainers is a popular JVM testing library that provides lightweight, throwaway instances of common databases, Selenium web browsers, or anything else that can run in a Docker container. In this talk, I will briefly go throught the past, present and the future of the library.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Road to Reliability: Infrastructure Testing explained</title>
      <link>https://devops-gathering.io/talks/infrastructure-testing/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://devops-gathering.io/talks/infrastructure-testing/</guid>
      <description>For years, there has been a shift to &amp;ldquo;Infrastructure as Code (IaC)&amp;rdquo;. The code we write daily is not just the application itself, but also definition of whatever Cloud Infrastructure the application needs. Tools like Terraform, Pulumi or Cloud APIs support this approach. The code base we start with is often simple and clear, the resulting infrastructure predictable. Growing code bases, entangled components and more advanced language features such as conditional configurations make it increasingly hard to foretell if everything works as expected.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Take MicroProfile to the Clouds with Quarkus</title>
      <link>https://devops-gathering.io/talks/take-microprofile-to-the-clouds-with-quarkus/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://devops-gathering.io/talks/take-microprofile-to-the-clouds-with-quarkus/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;Supersonic Subatomic Java&amp;rdquo; claims Quarkus, the new star at the sky of microservice frameworks. And yes, you are able to build services easily and quickly, which are small, fast and reactive, while still leveraging the JEE programming model. Quarkus is based on MicroProfile containing a subset of Jakarta EE and various extensions for building distributed, cloud-ready (micro) services. Devs will love the convenient developer mode and ops will love the seamless container integration and blazing fast startup in native mode.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hacking Terraform - Engineer your Migration to IaC</title>
      <link>https://devops-gathering.io/talks/hacking-terraform/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://devops-gathering.io/talks/hacking-terraform/</guid>
      <description>Infrastructure as Code (IaC) is considered the predominant approach to manage Cloud Infrastructure at large scale. Terraform is the market-leading tool implementing this approach, including support for all big Clouds Providers. It is extremely convenient to start new projects from scratch and automate your infrastructure right away. But what if you started without? What if you want to manage big amounts of pre-existing Cloud resources with Terraform?
Terraform&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;import&amp;rdquo; command is one building block, but using it manually for many resources is very tedious and error-prone.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>&#39;Serverless&#39; and &#39;Functions as a Service&#39; with OpenFaaS</title>
      <link>https://devops-gathering.io/talks/openfaas/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://devops-gathering.io/talks/openfaas/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;Serverless&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;Functions as a Service&amp;rdquo; are the latest craze, especially in particular the big players like Amazon with AWS Lamda, Google with Google Functions and Microsoft with Azure Functions come around the corner and give their customers, at the first look, easy to use frameworks. But how can you use your own, already existing infrastructure to go &amp;ldquo;serverless&amp;rdquo;? With OpenFaaS a flexible framework exists which you can use to set up your own “Serverless” infrastructure on your existing Docker Swarm or Kubernetes cluster, either on your local development hardware or in your datacenter.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Testable Kubernetes Operators</title>
      <link>https://devops-gathering.io/talks/testable-kubernetes-operators/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://devops-gathering.io/talks/testable-kubernetes-operators/</guid>
      <description>Kubernetes operators have been used more commonly throughout the Kubernetes community to automate workflows, manage applications and infrastructure. These usecases have produced complex operators which need to be tested properly to ensure that they are working as intended. Testing operators in practice has been a difficult task - unit tests can only cover a limited scope of logic (even with mocks like k8sfakeclient) and e2e tests (while offering a wider scope) are plagued by a common issue: flapping.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Containerized Pipelines Can Boost Your CI/CD</title>
      <link>https://devops-gathering.io/talks/how-containerized-pipelines-can-boost-your-cicd/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://devops-gathering.io/talks/how-containerized-pipelines-can-boost-your-cicd/</guid>
      <description>Learn how to eliminate any dependencies on your CI/CD build nodes and don’t bother yourself with multiple versions of your toolchain and any corresponding constraints. Walk away with knowledge and best practices that will help you to optimize your builds and deployments with containerized pipelines! Use containerized Gitlab CI/CD pipelines and Kaniko to move your build and deployment workloads into your Kubernetes cluster. Build your apps and infrastructure without any external dependencies and constraints.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A cloud architect perspective on transitioning from legacy systems into a cloud native world</title>
      <link>https://devops-gathering.io/talks/from-legacy-into-cloud-native-world/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://devops-gathering.io/talks/from-legacy-into-cloud-native-world/</guid>
      <description>We often accumulate a set of systems over years of gradual development. Each generation of developers added its contribution to a code base that is beyond rewritable, and in some aspects does not make sense to our end-users. In addition, these systems often embody years of on-premise practices and assumptions, that grew into a culture that eternalizes its inherent flaws. For example the old premise systems rely on replication to mitigate the fact they are no highly available or built for high loads.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tracing: A journey to tactical insight</title>
      <link>https://devops-gathering.io/talks/tracing-a-journey-to-tactical-insight/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://devops-gathering.io/talks/tracing-a-journey-to-tactical-insight/</guid>
      <description>G Data is taking you on a journey about gaining tactical insight into business processes by the means of using OpenTracing (Jaeger). Part of this talk will be a short introduction about tracing in general and how it can help you to solve certain use cases. Concepts about stream processing of trace events will be included.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lightning Talks</title>
      <link>https://devops-gathering.io/talks/lightning-talks-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://devops-gathering.io/talks/lightning-talks-2/</guid>
      <description>TBA</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Oh, excuse me - there was an error in newsletter sign up</title>
      <link>https://devops-gathering.io/newsletter-subscription-error/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://devops-gathering.io/newsletter-subscription-error/</guid>
      <description>Please try again or contact us at marketing@communicode.de</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Please confirm your registration</title>
      <link>https://devops-gathering.io/newsletter-subscription/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://devops-gathering.io/newsletter-subscription/</guid>
      <description>Thank you for subscribing to our DevOps Gathering Newsletter - your registration is almost complete.
In order to prevent misuse, we have just sent you a confirmation link at your specified e-mail address.
Please confirm the receipt of our newsletter with the verification link.
By entering your e-mail address, clicking on the &amp;ldquo;subscribe to newsletter&amp;rdquo; button and subsequent confirmation of the verification link, you agree that communicode AG will provide you with information about the DevOps Gathering to your given e-mail address.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Timeout for the confirmation of the newsletter</title>
      <link>https://devops-gathering.io/newsletter-subscription-timeout/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://devops-gathering.io/newsletter-subscription-timeout/</guid>
      <description>We are sorry. There was a timeout during your newsletter registration.
For privacy and security reasons, newsletter applications must be verified within 30 days.
You will need to subscribe to the DevOps Gathering Newsletter and confirm to receive it again.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>You have successfully unsubscribed from the newsletter.</title>
      <link>https://devops-gathering.io/newsletter-optout-success/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://devops-gathering.io/newsletter-optout-success/</guid>
      <description>Too bad that you no longer wish to receive our information DevOps Gathering.
We hope to see you soon anyway.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Your e-mail address already exists</title>
      <link>https://devops-gathering.io/newsletter-double-confirmation/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://devops-gathering.io/newsletter-double-confirmation/</guid>
      <description>We appreciate your interest, but apparently you have already registered for our newsletter.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Your newsletter registration is complete</title>
      <link>https://devops-gathering.io/newsletter-subscription-thankyou/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://devops-gathering.io/newsletter-subscription-thankyou/</guid>
      <description>Thank you for signing up for our newsletter.
You can unsubscribe from this mailing list at any time using the unsubscribe link within the newsletter.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Student Ticket Sponsoring</title>
      <link>https://devops-gathering.io/student-ticket-sponsoring/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Nov 2017 09:28:54 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://devops-gathering.io/student-ticket-sponsoring/</guid>
      <description>Dear DevOps-Friends and students!
We are happy to have the opportunity to sponsor your attendance for the next DevOps Gathering 2020 :-)
You have the chance to get one sponsored ticket for the conference days!
Want to win one ticket? Then please answer the following questions and send it to: info@devops-gathering.io
Please attach a copy of your valid studentID!
 At which university are you studying? What are you studying?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Videos, photos and impressions of the DevOps Gathering</title>
      <link>https://devops-gathering.io/media-and-photos/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Aug 2017 09:28:54 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://devops-gathering.io/media-and-photos/</guid>
      <description>DevOps Gathering 2019 Blogposts and impressions  DevOps Gathering 2019 - Workshops, bees and everything in between Bee involved with the DevOps Gathering 2019 Speaker slides Blogpost by cloudogu  Recorded conference talks Talks - Playlist
 Lightning Talks - Playlist
 
Photos    Dog19 1
      Dog19 10
      Dog19 11
      Dog19 12</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Accommodations</title>
      <link>https://devops-gathering.io/accommodations/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Jan 2017 12:28:54 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://devops-gathering.io/accommodations/</guid>
      <description>Accommodations &amp;amp; Hotels Art Hotel Tucholsky Viktoriastraße 73, 44787 Bochum
Booking
| website: www.art-hotel-tucholsky.de | e-mail: info@art-hotel-tucholsky.de or sb@bjw-gastronomie.de | phone: +49 (0)234 964360 or +49 (0)234 5306670
acora Hotel und Wohnen Nordring 44 – 50, 44787 Bochum
Booking
| e-mail: bochum@acora.de | phone: +49 (0)234&amp;frasl;68 96-985</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>After Conference Reception</title>
      <link>https://devops-gathering.io/after-conference/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Jan 2017 12:28:54 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://devops-gathering.io/after-conference/</guid>
      <description>6:30pm - 10:00 pm at G Data Campus After a day of great talks, nothing sounds better than grabbing a cold beer, tasty food and networking with fellow developers and enthusiasts. Luckily, the DevOps Gathering Reception is just that.
G Data provides awesome people, tasty food and high quality drinks. Feel free to join us and to talk with other DevOps interested people, including the speakers. Socialize and make new friends.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Conference Code of Conduct </title>
      <link>https://devops-gathering.io/code-of-conduct/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Jan 2017 12:28:54 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://devops-gathering.io/code-of-conduct/</guid>
      <description>All attendees, speakers, sponsors and volunteers at our conference are required to agree with the following code of conduct. Organisers will enforce this code throughout the event. We are expecting cooperation from all participants to help ensuring a safe environment for everybody.
Need Help? We have a dedicated team that takes care of your safety. If you experience harassment or other Code of Conduct violations, please contact the care team (twitter: @DevOpsGathering; e-mail: care@devops-gathering.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>General terms and conditions</title>
      <link>https://devops-gathering.io/general-terms-and-conditions/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Jan 2017 12:28:54 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://devops-gathering.io/general-terms-and-conditions/</guid>
      <description>By signing up for a communicode AG conference and workshop, the following terms and conditions will be agreed upon.
Please read these conditions carefully!
SCOPE OF APPLICATION The organizer of the conference and workshops is
communicode AG (further on in this document: communicode).
For the participation in a communicode workshop or conference, the following “general conditions for communicode conferences and workshops” apply, which govern the contractual basis between communicode and a participant.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to become a sponsor? </title>
      <link>https://devops-gathering.io/sponsoring/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Jan 2017 12:28:54 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://devops-gathering.io/sponsoring/</guid>
      <description>Sponsoring DevOps Gathering We are hosting a self organized and non-profit conference providing a platform for the DevOps Community and the DevOps revolution. We like to bring you all together: students, developers, CTOs and experts to discuss the hot topics Docker, Kubernetes, Microservices, Clouds and everything else regarding DevOps. Let&amp;rsquo;s share the best practices, the know-how and learn from those who know best!
After this year‘s successful and sold out community conference, we are now preparing the fourth round of the DevOps Gathering 2020.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pricing &amp; Registration</title>
      <link>https://devops-gathering.io/tickets/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Jan 2017 12:28:54 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://devops-gathering.io/tickets/</guid>
      <description>Price Categories &amp;amp; Information All conference and workshop tickets include food, drinks, great talks and Wi-Fi.
The 1 Day Ticket includes the Workshop Day. The 2 Day Ticket includes the Conference Days and the evening reception. The 3 Day Ticket includes everything: The pre-conference workshops, the Conference Days and also the evening event.
   Tickets (all prices excl. VAT) Early Bird (till February 7th) Standard     3 Day Ticket (Workshops &amp;amp; Conference) 499 € 549 €   2 Day Ticket (Conference) 299 € 349 €   1 Day Ticket (Pre-Conference Workshops) 349 € 399 €   Student 3 Day Ticket (Workshops &amp;amp; Conference) 129 € 149 €   Student 2 Day Ticket (Conference) 59 € 79 €   Student 1 Day Ticket (Pre-Conference Workshops) 79 € 99 €    Students have to present a valid student picture ID and proof of full-time attendance at an accredited university to register for the student tickets.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Privacy Policy</title>
      <link>https://devops-gathering.io/privacy-policy/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Jan 2017 12:28:54 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://devops-gathering.io/privacy-policy/</guid>
      <description>Data Privacy Policy This page is operated by communicode AG.
Data protection is of a particularly high priority for the management of the communicode AG. The use of the Internet pages of the communicode AG is possible without any indication of personal data; however, if a data subject wants to use special enterprise services via our website, processing of personal data could become necessary. If the processing of personal data is necessary and there is no statutory basis for such processing, we generally obtain consent from the data subject.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Imprint</title>
      <link>https://devops-gathering.io/imprint/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Dec 2016 19:26:55 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://devops-gathering.io/imprint/</guid>
      <description>Legal information that is necessary for a German site  Information required under § 5 Para. 1 of the German Telemedia Act:
communicode AG Rellinghauser Straße 332
45136 Essen/NRW
Germany
Phone: +49 201 84188 188
Fax: +49 201 84188 199
Email: info@communicode.de
Office: Essen
Amtsgericht Essen, HRB 24420
USt-IdNr. DE-28730918
Represented by the board:
Stefan Belmann (CEO), Armin Peiker
Supervisory board: Dr. Jochen Melchior (Chairman), Dr. Andreas Radmacher, Volker Scholz</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Venue</title>
      <link>https://devops-gathering.io/venue/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Dec 2016 19:26:55 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://devops-gathering.io/venue/</guid>
      <description>Pre-Conference-Workshops on Monday (March 11, 2019) Zentrum für IT Sicherheit (ZITS) Lise-Meitner-Allee 4 44801 Bochum
 Website     Dog sweets
      Itz eingang
      Itz workshop
      Workshop day
      Workshop present
      Workshop raum
                                    Conference on Tuesday and Wednesday (March 12 - 13, 2019) G Data Campus, Königsallee 178b, 44799 Bochum</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://devops-gathering.io/imprint-de/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://devops-gathering.io/imprint-de/</guid>
      <description>Impressum Angaben gemäß § 5 TMG: bee42 solutions GmbH Am Josephsschacht 72 44879 Bochum
Gesellschaftsform: Gesellschaft mit beschränkter Haftung
Vertreten durch: Peter Rossbach
Kontakt: Telefon: +49 157 72 54 92 63 E-Mail: info@bee42.com
Registereintrag: Eintragung im Handelsregister. Registergericht:Amtsgericht Bochum Registernummer: HRB 14047
Umsatzsteuer-ID: Umsatzsteuer-Identifikationsnummer gemäß §27 a Umsatzsteuergesetz: DE 28 49 32 374
Quelle: Mit dem von eRecht24 bereitgestellten Impressum-Generator erzeugt.
Haftungsausschluss: Haftung für Inhalte
Die Inhalte unserer Seiten wurden mit größter Sorgfalt erstellt.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://devops-gathering.io/speakers/burkhard-noltensmeier/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://devops-gathering.io/speakers/burkhard-noltensmeier/</guid>
      <description>Burkhard (avowed since 1993 Linux Evangelist) founded after studying computer science at the University of Hagen 1994 teuto.net Network Services GmbH in Bielefeld. His focus are new technologies and he is always one of the first to try them out. Developing and operating clouds based on Openstack and Kubernetes are his goal. Burkhard is official corporate sponsor of the OpenStack Foundation, member of Cloud Native Foundation (CNCF) and his company is qualified as a Kubernetes Certified Service Provider.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://devops-gathering.io/speakers/christian-wansart/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://devops-gathering.io/speakers/christian-wansart/</guid>
      <description>Christian Wansart is an Enterprise Developer who works for the open knowledge GmbH. He is a fullstack developer working in backend, frontend and DevOps areas. He uses container technology for years and works with test frameworks to develop stable software with high quality.
 Conference Talk: The Software Factory - Why technology is not enough Halfday-Workshop: Testing with Containers  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://devops-gathering.io/speakers/constantin-weisser/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://devops-gathering.io/speakers/constantin-weisser/</guid>
      <description>Constantin Weisser is a Consultant and Trainer for Novatec Consulting GmbH, based in Germany. He is accompanying customers on their journey to modern software development. He focuses on methods and tools around Software Delivery, i.e. covering all the way from the source code to a running application in the Cloud. Constantin advocates tailored tooling, step-by-step automation and an engineering approaches to speed up software development and delivery, enabling teams to ship high quality applications.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://devops-gathering.io/speakers/dirk-weil/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://devops-gathering.io/speakers/dirk-weil/</guid>
      <description>Dirk Weil has been working as a Java consultant since 1998. As Managing Director of GEDOPLAN GmbH, he is responsible for the conception and realization of Java based information systems. With many years of experience in developing sophisticated business solutions he and his team are competent partners and recognized experts for Java and JEE. He is a book author, writes articles for magazines and speaks at conferences and user groups. He works as trainer for GEDOPLAN IT Training holding various Java and JEE seminars and workshops.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://devops-gathering.io/speakers/ema-rimeike/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://devops-gathering.io/speakers/ema-rimeike/</guid>
      <description> Lighting Talk: Don&amp;rsquo;t Shift Left, START Left  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://devops-gathering.io/speakers/eyal-liebermann/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://devops-gathering.io/speakers/eyal-liebermann/</guid>
      <description>Eyal Liebermann is the Software Architect of SAP Universal ID. An SAP Program that aims to streamline the login and authorization experience across SAP cloud services. Eyal has a unique passion for taking complex legacy systems and transforming them into coherent performant ones. This passion is supported by twenty years of experience, as a developer, a team lead and a software architect, during which he was witnessing grandiose rewrite plans go wary, whereas persistent refactoring efforts seemed to be achieving ambitious goals.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://devops-gathering.io/speakers/florian-kuckelkorn/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://devops-gathering.io/speakers/florian-kuckelkorn/</guid>
      <description>Since 2017 Florian Kuckelkorn is working as a technical coordinator and controller for Protection Technologies (G DATA CyberDefense AG). His primary focus and interest lies on G DATA&amp;rsquo;s Protection Technologies especially on evaluating, tracking and improving backend business processes. Since early age he is technical fascinated and self taught most his knowledge, he has today. He is actively interested in interdisciplinary areas of work and likes the inspiration of dealing with pioneer topics.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://devops-gathering.io/speakers/halil-cem-gursoy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://devops-gathering.io/speakers/halil-cem-gursoy/</guid>
      <description>Halil is a Senior Solution Architect at OPITZ CONSULTING and is already active as Software Developer and Architect since over 20 years. His focus is on large distributed enterprise systems, mostly written in Java, but has wrote more productive infrastructure code in Go, Python or Ruby as classic enterprise Java stuff in the last years.
 Conference Talk: &amp;ldquo;Serverless&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;Functions as a Service&amp;rdquo; with OpenFaaS  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://devops-gathering.io/speakers/kevin-wittek/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://devops-gathering.io/speakers/kevin-wittek/</guid>
      <description>Testcontainers co-maintainer and Testcontainers-Spock author. Software Craftsman and testing fan. Loves to play the electric guitar and is a musician in his second life. Found his own company during his university years, developing mobile apps and client-server applications, which lead to his discovery of Grails and the Groovy ecosystem. Fell in love with TDD because of Spock.
After many years working in the industry as an engineer, Kevin is now doing his PhD at RWTH Aachen on the topic of verification of Smart Contracts and is leading the Blockchain Research Lab at the Institute for Internet Security in Gelsenkirchen at the Westphalian University of Applied Sciences.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://devops-gathering.io/speakers/konstantin-diener/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://devops-gathering.io/speakers/konstantin-diener/</guid>
      <description>Konstantin Diener is CTO at cosee. He has been developing software for more than 15 years. His CTO role made him shift his focus to (agile) leadership topics and how to create a productive environment for self-organised engineering teams. Konstantin speaks at conferences and is author of „DevOps Stories“, a column about culture, leadership, agile and DevOps.
 Conference Talk: The first decade of DevOps is over!   </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://devops-gathering.io/speakers/maggie-otoole/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://devops-gathering.io/speakers/maggie-otoole/</guid>
      <description>Maggie O’Toole is a Solutions Architect for AWS in Germany, and has been with AWS since 2017. She enjoys helping customers improve their business and IT solutions with the AWS Cloud, and specializes in Containers.
 Halfday-Workshop: Amazon EKS Workshop  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://devops-gathering.io/speakers/manuel-zapf/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://devops-gathering.io/speakers/manuel-zapf/</guid>
      <description>Traefik&amp;rsquo;s Solution Architect at Containous. His special interest is in deploying applications scalable by using cloud and container technologies. Gopher lover.
 Conference Talk: Routing Your Microservices Architecture to Ease DevOps Enterprise Transformation  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://devops-gathering.io/speakers/marcel-mueller/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://devops-gathering.io/speakers/marcel-mueller/</guid>
      <description>Marcel is a Platform Engineer at Giant Swarm where he works on Kubernetes Operators and focuses on all things Release Engineering. He is passionate about infrastructure automation in distributed systems and building fault-tolerant software. Marcel is excited to share the learnings he has made along the way. During the last two years he has been closely following Kubernetes upstream developments such as Cluster-API and KIND.
 Halfday Workshop: Introduction to Kubernetes Operators Conference Talk: Testable Kubernetes Operators  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://devops-gathering.io/speakers/mario-kleinsasser/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://devops-gathering.io/speakers/mario-kleinsasser/</guid>
      <description>Mario Kleinsasser is the team leader of a small cloud solution operations team within the IT department of the STRABAG SE construction company. Since more than 15 years he&amp;rsquo;s surfing the wave of change with passion. Mario was a speaker at the DevOps Gathering 2018 and 2019 in Bochum Germany, he is the organizer of the Docker South Austria Meetup and he also contributes code for various Open Source projects, like CoreDNS and others.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://devops-gathering.io/speakers/martin-valdes-de-leon/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://devops-gathering.io/speakers/martin-valdes-de-leon/</guid>
      <description>Originally from Argentina, Martin is a Senior Solution Architect with AWS. Prior to joining AWS he worked in various development and architecture roles, specializing in Microservices, Containers and Kubernetes. He now helps enterprise customers expand their businesses with the AWS cloud.
 Halfday-Workshop: Amazon EKS Workshop  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://devops-gathering.io/speakers/matthias-simonis/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://devops-gathering.io/speakers/matthias-simonis/</guid>
      <description>Matthias Simonis works at G DATA since 2016 with a primary focus on the automation of everything. This starts with the setup of infrastructure and ends with the development and deployment of services for automated data processing.
Matthias Simonis is a self taught tech enthusiast that embraces new and old technology to get stuff done.
 Halfday Workshop: Ansible - Testing with Molecule  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://devops-gathering.io/speakers/matthias-wessendorf/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://devops-gathering.io/speakers/matthias-wessendorf/</guid>
      <description>Matthias Wessendorf works on the Messaging team at Red Hat, focusing on event-driven architectures, data-streaming and serverless workloads. He is an active contributor to the Knative project. Matthias is a regular speaker at international conferences and is a long standing member of the Apache Software Foundation.
 Conference Talk: Knative Eventing Deep Dive  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://devops-gathering.io/speakers/niclas-mietz/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://devops-gathering.io/speakers/niclas-mietz/</guid>
      <description>Niclas is a DevOps Engineer, Docker expert and open source maintainer. He accelerates deployment processes in IT projects and systems. With his expertise regarding GitLab/CI pipelines he is an outstanding expert in Continuous Delivery and Continuous Integration.
 Halfday-Workshop: Kubernetes 101 Conference Talk: Lets Go Knative  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://devops-gathering.io/speakers/nico-meisenzahl/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://devops-gathering.io/speakers/nico-meisenzahl/</guid>
      <description>Nico Meisenzahl works as Senior Cloud &amp;amp; DevOps Consultant at white duck. As an elected Docker Community Leader and GitLab Hero, his current passion is for topics around Kubernetes, CI/CD, Automation, DevOps, and Cloud.
Nico is a frequent speaker at conferences, user group events and Meetups in Europe and the United States.
 Conference Talk: How Containerized Pipelines Can Boost Your CI/CD  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://devops-gathering.io/speakers/nils-bokermann/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://devops-gathering.io/speakers/nils-bokermann/</guid>
      <description>Nils Bokermann is an IT Consultant on a freelance basis. He provides his customers with advice on architecture and methodics. He questions hype based decisions and is therefor known as an advocatus diaboli.
 Conference Talk: Infrastructure as Microservices - Alternatives to the Monolithic Kubernetes  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://devops-gathering.io/speakers/peter-rossbach/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://devops-gathering.io/speakers/peter-rossbach/</guid>
      <description>As Principal Consultant and Director of Software Development at Communicode AG and also System Architect, DevOps Engineer, Apache Member, Apache Tomcat Committer, Infracoder and Docker Influencer, Peter can rely on a long-lasting and remarkable experience. With his skills he inspires not only the communicode, but also our customers to top performances.
 Conference Talk: Cloud Native Ecosystem  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://devops-gathering.io/speakers/philipp-krenn/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://devops-gathering.io/speakers/philipp-krenn/</guid>
      <description>Philipp lives to demo interesting technology. Having worked as a web, infrastructure, and database engineer for over ten years, Philipp is now working as a developer advocate at Elastic — the company behind the Elastic Stack consisting of Elasticsearch, Kibana, Beats, and Logstash.
 Conference Talk: From Containers to Kubernetes Operators  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://devops-gathering.io/speakers/rainer-stropek/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://devops-gathering.io/speakers/rainer-stropek/</guid>
      <description>Rainer Stropek has been an entrepreneur in the IT industry for more than twenty years. During this time, he founded and managed several IT service companies and is currently developing the award-winning Software time cockpit in his company software architects together with his team. Rainer holds degrees from the Technical College of MIS, Leonding (AT) and the University of Derby (UK). He is the author of several books and articles in magazines around Microsoft .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://devops-gathering.io/speakers/robert-douglass/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://devops-gathering.io/speakers/robert-douglass/</guid>
      <description>Robert Douglass has been deeply involved with open source software since 2004. He was the author of the first book published about Drupal, &amp;ldquo;Building Online Communities in Drupal, Wordpress, PhpBB&amp;rdquo; (Apress, 2005), is a core code contributor to 4 different Drupal versions, and the original author of the Memcache and Solr modules for Drupal. Robert has also served as a member of the Drupal Association, a founding member of the German Drupal Association, and a member of the Drupal Security team.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://devops-gathering.io/speakers/roland-huss/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://devops-gathering.io/speakers/roland-huss/</guid>
      <description>Dr. Roland Huß is a principal software engineer at Red Hat and a member of the serverless team for coding on Knative. He has been developing in Java for over twenty years now. However, he has never forgotten his roots as a system administrator. Roland is an active open source contributor, lead developer of the JMX-HTTP bridge Jolokia and some popular Java build tools for creating container images and deploying them on Kubernetes and OpenShift.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://devops-gathering.io/speakers/stefan-hausotte/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://devops-gathering.io/speakers/stefan-hausotte/</guid>
      <description>Stefan Hausotte is the lead for “Automated Threat Analysis” at G DATA, where he plans and coordinates the development of automated malware analysis and classification tools. He is an active open source committer in different projects related to security, .NET and software development areas. Furthermore he teaches IT-Security at the Technical University of Dortmund and is a frequent speaker about security related topics at conferences and fairs. He believes that a graph is the natural representation of the different interconnections between malware and malicious actors and a graph database is the right approach as an underlying technology for efficient malware analysis at large scale.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://devops-gathering.io/speakers/stephan-mueller/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://devops-gathering.io/speakers/stephan-mueller/</guid>
      <description>Stephan Müller is an Enterprise Architect who works for the open knowledge GmbH. He has worked as an architect, product owner, project manager and coach in numerous enterprise projects for more than a decade. His main interests are architectures, new technologies and clean code.
 Conference Talk: The Software Factory - Why technology is not enough Halfday-Workshop: Testing with Containers  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://devops-gathering.io/speakers/thomas-peitz/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://devops-gathering.io/speakers/thomas-peitz/</guid>
      <description>Thomas Peitz is a Site Reliability Engineer at InVision AG in Düsseldorf. He loves talking about DevOps, infrastructure, containers and serverless, which is why he is also running plenty of meetups around those topics.
 Halfday-Workshop: Going Serverless  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Container Open Space</title>
      <link>https://devops-gathering.io/openspace/container-open-space/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://devops-gathering.io/openspace/container-open-space/</guid>
      <description>WHAT IS AN OPEN SPACE? What do you need to bring with you for the conference? -&amp;gt; Only you, good ideas and curiosity! :-)
Where can I find more information about the open space? Here you can find definitions, videos and more information about the format open space : * https://de.wikipedia.org/wiki/Open_Space * http://www.agonda.de/open-space/open-space.html * https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=eZD0PtnN1vQ
An Open Space is a simple and productive way for hosting knowledge events. Participants and experts will create and manage together their own agenda of parallel working sessions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Feedback</title>
      <link>https://devops-gathering.io/feedback/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://devops-gathering.io/feedback/</guid>
      <description>In order to provide you with the best workshops and conference possible, we need your feedback
Thanks a lot for your support in advance, it only takes 3 minutes :)
Feedback form will be here when the conference has started
Link for mobile &amp;ndash;&amp;gt;
Loading... </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Get in touch</title>
      <link>https://devops-gathering.io/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://devops-gathering.io/contact/</guid>
      <description>Contact If you have any further questions, please don&amp;rsquo;t hesitate to contact us. Thank you!
e-mail: info@devops-gathering.io phone: +49 151 16147053
Let&amp;rsquo;s keep in touch Be the first to know about our events! Get updates on schedule announcements, speakers, specials and registration discounts. Subscribe and join the DevOps Gathering community:
  function onSubmit(token) { document.getElementById(&#34;displayform&#34;).submit(); }  E-mail address *  Tracking agreement according to GDPR. We use your data exclusively for the personalization of the newsletter.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sponsors</title>
      <link>https://devops-gathering.io/sponsors/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://devops-gathering.io/sponsors/</guid>
      <description>The Conference Crew would like to take the time to thank all of our awesome sponsors whose sponsorship helped and supported the last two DevOps Gathering conferences.
We are now preparing the third edition of the DevOps Gathering. As a community conference with a low entrance fee, we depend on sponsors for making this event possible.
We would be happy and grateful to have YOU as a supporter of this great community!</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>