<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Devops Gathering 2019 | March 11 - 13, 2019 in Bochum</title>
    <link>https://devops-gathering.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Devops Gathering 2019 | March 11 - 13, 2019 in Bochum</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 29 Nov 2017 09:28:54 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://devops-gathering.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Student Ticket Sponsoring</title>
      <link>https://devops-gathering.io/student-ticket-sponsoring/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Nov 2017 09:28:54 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://devops-gathering.io/student-ticket-sponsoring/</guid>
      <description> Dear DevOps-Friends and students!
We are happy to have the opportunity to sponsor your attendance for the next DevOps Gathering 2019 :-)
You have the chance to get one sponsored ticket for the conference days! Want to win one ticket? Then please fill out the following application form and send us afterwards your student-ID (mail to: info@devops-gathering.io)
 Click here to fill in the application  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Workshop Requirements | February 19th</title>
      <link>https://devops-gathering.io/workshop-requirements/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Nov 2017 09:28:54 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://devops-gathering.io/workshop-requirements/</guid>
      <description>Workshop: Building a Self-Sufficient System by Viktor Farcic  https://github.com/vfarcic/vfarcic.github.io/blob/master/devops22/REQS.md  Workshop: Introduction into Kubernetes by Thomas Fricke  either a Laptop with at least 8 GB of memory and a preinstalled minikube for your operating system. Installation instructions are here https://github.com/kubernetes/minikube or alternatively access to Kubernetes in a cloud like GCE. Instructions for GKE are herehttps://cloud.google.com/kubernetes-engine/docs/quickstart and an installed version of Kubectl https://kubernetes.io/docs/tasks/tools/install-kubectl  Workshop: Groovy Integration Testing with Docker and TestContainers by Kevin Wittek and Matthias Rottländer As this is a hands-on workshop, it is essential that you bring a prepared workstation, containing the following software:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Videos, photos and impressions of the DevOps Gathering</title>
      <link>https://devops-gathering.io/media-and-photos/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Aug 2017 09:28:54 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://devops-gathering.io/media-and-photos/</guid>
      <description>Blogpost about the first DevOps Gathering in 2017:  Workshop Day Docker on Windows Workshop Conference Day Open Space 2017  Recorded conference talks of the DevOps Gathering 2017:  Pictures and impressions of the DevOps Gathering 2017:    Attendee with dev ops gathering t shirt
      Attendees watching dev ops gathering conference talks
      Coffee break on workshop day dev ops gathering</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Accommodations</title>
      <link>https://devops-gathering.io/accommodations/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Jan 2017 12:28:54 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://devops-gathering.io/accommodations/</guid>
      <description>Accommodations &amp;amp; Hotels Art Hotel Tucholsky Viktoriastraße 73, 44787 Bochum
Booking
| website: www.art-hotel-tucholsky.de | e-mail: info@art-hotel-tucholsky.de or sb@bjw-gastronomie.de | phone: +49 (0)234 964360 or +49 (0)234 5306670
acora Hotel und Wohnen Nordring 44 – 50, 44787 Bochum
Booking
| e-mail: bochum@acora.de | phone: +49 (0)234&amp;frasl;68 96-985</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>After Conference Reception</title>
      <link>https://devops-gathering.io/after-conference/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Jan 2017 12:28:54 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://devops-gathering.io/after-conference/</guid>
      <description>6:30pm - 10:00 pm at G Data Campus After a day of great talks, nothing sounds better than grabbing a cold beer, tasty food and networking with fellow developers and enthusiasts. Luckily, the DevOps Gathering Reception is just that.
G Data provides awesome people, tasty food and high quality drinks. Feel free to join us and to talk with other DevOps interested people, including the speakers. Socialize and make new friends.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Conference Code of Conduct </title>
      <link>https://devops-gathering.io/code-of-conduct/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Jan 2017 12:28:54 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://devops-gathering.io/code-of-conduct/</guid>
      <description>All attendees, speakers, sponsors and volunteers at our conference are required to agree with the following code of conduct. Organisers will enforce this code throughout the event. We are expecting cooperation from all participants to help ensuring a safe environment for everybody.
Need Help? We have a dedicated team that takes care of your safety. If you experience harassment or other Code of Conduct violations, please contact the care team (twitter: @DevOpsGathering; e-mail: care@devops-gathering.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>General terms and conditions</title>
      <link>https://devops-gathering.io/general-terms-and-conditions/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Jan 2017 12:28:54 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://devops-gathering.io/general-terms-and-conditions/</guid>
      <description>By signing up for a bee42 solutions GmbH conference and workshop, the following terms and conditions will be agreed upon.
Please read these conditions carefully!
SCOPE OF APPLICATION The organizer of the conference and workshops is
bee42 solutions GmbH, Am Josephsschacht 72 D-44879 Bochum, Germany (further on in this document: bee42).
For the participation in a bee42 workshop or conference, the following “general conditions for bee42 conferences and workshops” apply, which govern the contractual basis between bee42 and a participant.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to become a sponsor? </title>
      <link>https://devops-gathering.io/sponsoring/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Jan 2017 12:28:54 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://devops-gathering.io/sponsoring/</guid>
      <description>Sponsoring DevOps Gathering We are hosting a self organized and non-profit conference providing a platform for the DevOps Community and the DevOps revolution. We like to bring you all together: students, developers, CTOs and experts to discuss the hot topics Docker, Kubernetes, Microservices, Clouds and everything else regarding DevOps. Let&amp;rsquo;s share the best practices, the know-how and learn from those who know best!
After this year‘s successful and sold out community conference, we are now preparing the third round of the DevOps Gathering 2019.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pricing &amp; Registration</title>
      <link>https://devops-gathering.io/tickets/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Jan 2017 12:28:54 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://devops-gathering.io/tickets/</guid>
      <description>Price Categories &amp;amp; Information All conference and workshop tickets include food, drinks, great talks and Wi-Fi.
Monday (March 11th) - Pre-Conference Workshops
Tuesday (March 12th) - Conference Day and evening reception
Wednesday (March 13th) - Conference Day
The 2 Day Ticket includes the conference days and the evening reception. The 3 Day Ticket includes everything: The pre-conference workshops, the Conference Days and also the evening event.
   Tickets (all prices excl.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Privacy Policy</title>
      <link>https://devops-gathering.io/privacy-policy/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Jan 2017 12:28:54 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://devops-gathering.io/privacy-policy/</guid>
      <description>Data Privacy Policy Our website may be used without entering personal information. Different rules may apply to certain services on our site, however, and are explained separately below. We collect personal information from you (e.g. name, address, email address, telephone number, etc.) in accordance with the provisions of German data protection statutes. Information is considered personal if it can be associated exclusively to a specific natural person. The legal framework for data protection may be found in the German Federal Data Protection Act (BDSG) and the Telemedia Act (TMG).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Imprint</title>
      <link>https://devops-gathering.io/imprint/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Dec 2016 19:26:55 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://devops-gathering.io/imprint/</guid>
      <description>Legal information that is necessary for a German site  Information required under § 5 Para. 1 of the German Telemedia Act:
bee42 solutions gmbh Am Josephsschacht 72
D-44879 Bochum
Germany
Email: mailto:info@bee42.com
Phone +49(0)157-72 54 92 63
Geschäftsführer: Peter Rossbach, Georg Jürgens
Responsible for the content according to § 55 Abs. 2 RStV: bee42 solutions gmbh Am Josephsschacht 72
D-44879 Bochum
Germany
Geschäftsführer: Peter Rossbach, Georg Jürgens
VAT-ID according to §27 a Umsatzsteuergesetz: DE284932374</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Venue</title>
      <link>https://devops-gathering.io/venue/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Dec 2016 19:26:55 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://devops-gathering.io/venue/</guid>
      <description> Pre-Conference-Workshops on Monday (March 11, 2019) Zentrum für IT Sicherheit (ZITS) Lise-Meitner-Allee 4 44801 Bochum
 Website    
Conference on Tuesday and Wednesday (March 12 - 13, 2019) G Data Campus, Königsallee 178b, 44799 Bochum
 Directions   </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://devops-gathering.io/imprint-de/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://devops-gathering.io/imprint-de/</guid>
      <description>Impressum Angaben gemäß § 5 TMG: bee42 solutions GmbH Am Josephsschacht 72 44879 Bochum
Gesellschaftsform: Gesellschaft mit beschränkter Haftung
Vertreten durch: Peter Rossbach
Kontakt: Telefon: +49 157 72 54 92 63 E-Mail: info@bee42.com
Registereintrag: Eintragung im Handelsregister. Registergericht:Amtsgericht Bochum Registernummer: HRB 14047
Umsatzsteuer-ID: Umsatzsteuer-Identifikationsnummer gemäß §27 a Umsatzsteuergesetz: DE 28 49 32 374
Quelle: Mit dem von eRecht24 bereitgestellten Impressum-Generator erzeugt.
Haftungsausschluss: Haftung für Inhalte
Die Inhalte unserer Seiten wurden mit größter Sorgfalt erstellt.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://devops-gathering.io/speakers/niclas-mietz/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://devops-gathering.io/speakers/niclas-mietz/</guid>
      <description>Niclas is a DevOps Engineer, Docker expert and open source maintainer. He accelerates deployment processes in IT projects and systems. With his expertise regarding GitLab/CI pipelines he is an outstanding expert in Continuous Delivery and Continous Integration.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://devops-gathering.io/speakers/peter-rossbach/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://devops-gathering.io/speakers/peter-rossbach/</guid>
      <description>As founder of the bee42, System Architect, DevOps Engineer, Apache Member, Apache Tomcat Committer, Infracoder and Docker In uencer, Peter can rely on a long-lasting and remarkable experience. With his skills he inspires not only the bee42 crew, but also our customers to top performances.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Container Open Space</title>
      <link>https://devops-gathering.io/openspace/container-open-space/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://devops-gathering.io/openspace/container-open-space/</guid>
      <description>WHAT IS AN OPEN SPACE? What do you need to bring with you for the conference? -&amp;gt; Only you, good ideas and curiosity! :-)
Where can I find more information about the open space? Here you can find definitions, videos and more information about the format open space : * https://de.wikipedia.org/wiki/Open_Space * http://www.agonda.de/open-space/open-space.html * https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=eZD0PtnN1vQ
An Open Space is a simple and productive way for hosting knowledge events. Participants and experts will create and manage together their own agenda of parallel working sessions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Get in touch</title>
      <link>https://devops-gathering.io/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://devops-gathering.io/contact/</guid>
      <description>Contact Before contacting us, please make sure that you take a moment to look through the event pages as answers to a lot of questions are readily available. :-)
If you can&amp;rsquo;t find your answer, please don&amp;rsquo;t hesitate to contact us. Thank you!
e-mail: info@devops-gathering.io phone: +49 (0)176 34402658
Let&amp;rsquo;s keep in touch Be the first to know about our events! Get updates on schedule announcements, speakers, specials and registration discounts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sponsors</title>
      <link>https://devops-gathering.io/sponsors/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://devops-gathering.io/sponsors/</guid>
      <description>The Conference Crew would like to take the time to thank all of our awesome sponsors whose sponsorship helped and supported the first DevOps Gathering 2017. Thank you for making this great conference possible! :-) After this year‘s and first successful community conference, we are now preparing the second edition of the DevOps Gathering. As a community conference with a low entrance fee, we depend on sponsors for making this event possible.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>