<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Speakers-rsses on Devops Gathering 2018</title>
    <link>https://devops-gathering.io/speakers/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in Speakers-rsses on Devops Gathering 2018</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://devops-gathering.io/speakers/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://devops-gathering.io/speakers/Anton-Weiss/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://devops-gathering.io/speakers/Anton-Weiss/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;CEO and founding consultant at Otomato – the effective software delivery experts. Initiator of the first DevOps certification program in Israel. 17 years of industry experience both at large corporations and startups. Writer, trainer, speaker and a conference rockstar.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://devops-gathering.io/workshops/Workshop-Building-a-Modern-CI-CD-Pipeline-with-Docker-and-Kubernetes/&#34;&gt;Workshop: Building a Modern CI/CD Pipeline (with Docker and Kubernetes)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://devops-gathering.io/speakers/Govinda-Fichtner/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://devops-gathering.io/speakers/Govinda-Fichtner/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Senior DevOps &amp;amp; Cloud-Engineer at Paessler AG Govinda has been working in the IT industry for more than 18 years in many different roles such as developer, administrator, consultant, architect, trainer, project manager, team lead and CTO. Currently he is busy building www.my-prtg.com, which is an AWS-based SaaS infrastructure monitoring solution. Govinda is a certified Linux and AWS professional who has been working as a DevOps based on agile principles since 2005. As part of the Hypriot-Team and as organiser of the &amp;ldquo;DevOps Franken&amp;rdquo;- and &amp;ldquo;Docker Bamberg&amp;rdquo;-User-Groups he is organising workshops about Docker, IoT, DevOps and Cloud and also giving talks on a regular base about a broad range of subjects like Docker, IoT, AWS and Microservices.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://devops-gathering.io/talks/Docker-on-AWS/&#34;&gt;DOCKER@AWS - a look at the different options to run Docker in the Amazon Cloud&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://devops-gathering.io/speakers/Kevin-Wittek/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://devops-gathering.io/speakers/Kevin-Wittek/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Java developer and JVM fanboy since being introduced to the language back in  school 12 years ago. Found his own company during his university years, developing mobile apps and client-server applications, which lead to his discovery of Grails and the Groovy ecosystem. Fell in love with TDD because of Spock.
Nowadays Kevin is working at the cyber security company GDATA Advanced Analytics and focuses on topics such as software craftsmanship, infrastructure as code and continuous integration pipelines, trying to make the world a better place one container at a time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://devops-gathering.io/workshops/Workshop-Groovy-integration-testing-with-Docker-and-TestContainers/&#34;&gt;Groovy integration testing with Docker and TestContainers&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://devops-gathering.io/speakers/Matthias-Rottlaender/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://devops-gathering.io/speakers/Matthias-Rottlaender/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Jack-Of-All-Trades promoting perpetual pursuit of technical excellence.
Developer of Java systems since about 10 years ago.
Passionate usability nit-pick.
Zealot hooking everyone in his vicinity on testing.
Wholehearted embracer of agile principles.
Found his home at German cyber security service provider GDATA Advanced Analytics, where he can do all of the above on a daily basis.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://devops-gathering.io/workshops/Workshop-Groovy-integration-testing-with-Docker-and-TestContainers/&#34;&gt;Groovy integration testing with Docker and TestContainers&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://devops-gathering.io/speakers/Maykel-Moya/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://devops-gathering.io/speakers/Maykel-Moya/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Maykel studied Software Engineering in La Habana, Cuba. He is currently the Engineering Lead in ShuttleCloud Corp., a small company specialized
in migrating email and contacts at scale. If you have recently imported contacts or email to GMail, GContacts or Yahoo!, you have used ShuttleCloud services.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;His ongoing challenges are migrating the infrastructure to kubernetes and improve its overall reliability. Enhance the monitoring is one concrete front he is closely working with.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Being also a cryptocoin enthusiast, he tries to combine both worlds where there are an opportunity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://devops-gathering.io/talks/Monitoring-FairCoin-blockchain-with-Prometheus/&#34;&gt;Monitoring FairCoin blockchain with Prometheus&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://devops-gathering.io/speakers/Niclas-Mietz/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://devops-gathering.io/speakers/Niclas-Mietz/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Niclas is a DevOps Engineer, Docker expert and open source maintainer. He accelerates deployment processes in IT projects and systems. With his expertise regarding GitLab/CI pipelines he is an outstanding expert in Continuous Delivery and Continous Integration.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://devops-gathering.io/workshops/Workshop-GitLab-CI-Basics/&#34;&gt;Workshop: GitLab/CI Basics&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://devops-gathering.io/speakers/Nicolas-Byl/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://devops-gathering.io/speakers/Nicolas-Byl/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Nicolas Byl gained his first hands-on experiences at developing distributed systems during his studies in medical informatics. At codecentric AG he is working on cloud-native infrastructure for application development.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://devops-gathering.io/talks/Stateful-Applications-on-Kubernetes/&#34;&gt;Stateful Applications on Kubernetes&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://devops-gathering.io/speakers/Peter-Rossbach/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://devops-gathering.io/speakers/Peter-Rossbach/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As founder of the bee42, System Architect, DevOps Engineer, Apache Member, Apache Tomcat Committer, Infracoder and Docker In uencer, Peter can rely on a long-lasting and remarkable experience. With his skills he inspires not only the bee42 crew, but
also our customers to top performances.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://devops-gathering.io/talks/Container-Software-Supply-Chain/&#34;&gt;Container Software Supply Chain&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://devops-gathering.io/speakers/Roland-Huss/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://devops-gathering.io/speakers/Roland-Huss/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Dr. Roland Huß is a Principal Software Engineer at Red Hat working in the Fuse team. He has been developing in Java for twenty years now but never forgot his roots as system administrator.
Roland is an active open source contributor, lead developer of the JMX-HTTP bridge Jolokia and the popular fabric8io/docker-maven-plugin. And he loves chilli pepper.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://devops-gathering.io/talks/Kubernetes-Patterns/&#34;&gt;Kubernetes Patterns&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://devops-gathering.io/speakers/bjoern-rabenstein/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://devops-gathering.io/speakers/bjoern-rabenstein/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Björn is a Production Engineer at SoundCloud and a Prometheus developer. Previously, he was a Site Reliability Engineer at Google and a number cruncher for science.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://devops-gathering.io/talks/Modern-Monitoring-for-Dev-and-Ops/&#34;&gt;Modern Monitoring for Dev and Ops&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://devops-gathering.io/speakers/jan-bruder/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://devops-gathering.io/speakers/jan-bruder/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Jan Bruder is a Linux containers and open source enthusiast. He joined Rancher Labs in 2016 and is working with Rancher users all over Europe on adopting Linux containers in their production environments.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://devops-gathering.io/talks/Deploying-and-managing-production-grade-Kubernetes-clusters-with-Rancher/&#34;&gt;Deploying and managing production-grade Kubernetes clusters with Rancher&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://devops-gathering.io/speakers/joao-santos/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://devops-gathering.io/speakers/joao-santos/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Software Engineer at Zalando SE&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://devops-gathering.io/talks/CI-CD-at-Zalando/&#34;&gt;CI/CD at Zalando&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://devops-gathering.io/speakers/konstantin-diener/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://devops-gathering.io/speakers/konstantin-diener/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Konstantin is CTO at cosee and has been using Scrum, Kanban &amp;amp; Co for almost ten years. He writes and speaks about topics like Management 3.0, agile leadership and DevOps.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://devops-gathering.io/talks/Tear-down-silos-How-What-comes-next/&#34;&gt;Tear down silos! How? What comes next?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://devops-gathering.io/speakers/mario-kleinsasser/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://devops-gathering.io/speakers/mario-kleinsasser/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Mario Kleinsasser is the team leader of a small web-hosting department of a large construction company. He is a DevOps since more than 15 years and he started to use containers based on OpenVZ back in 2006. Through the transition and migration to Docker he transforms theoretical concepts into working durable Docker solutions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://devops-gathering.io/talks/Docker-Ops-unleashed/&#34;&gt;Docker: Ops unleashed&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://devops-gathering.io/speakers/philipp-garbe/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://devops-gathering.io/speakers/philipp-garbe/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Philipp works as Lead Platform Engineer at Scout24 in Munich. He is driven by technologies and tools that allows him to release faster and more often. He expects that every commit automatically goes into production and it shouldn&amp;rsquo;t surprise that he&amp;rsquo;s excited about microservices, Docker and the cloud. Affected by Pain Driven Development, Philipp believes that things need to be changed whenever the pain is big enough. As Docker Captain he also tries to share his knowledge and experience about Containers with the community.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://devops-gathering.io/talks/Managed-Container-Orchestration-with-ECS-at-Scout24/&#34;&gt;Managed Container Orchestration with ECS at Scout24&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>