<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Speakers on Devops Gathering 2020 | March 09 - 11, 2020 in Bochum</title>
    <link>https://devops-gathering.io/speakers/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Speakers on Devops Gathering 2020 | March 09 - 11, 2020 in Bochum</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="https://devops-gathering.io/speakers/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://devops-gathering.io/speakers/burkhard-noltensmeier/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://devops-gathering.io/speakers/burkhard-noltensmeier/</guid>
      <description>Burkhard (avowed since 1993 Linux Evangelist) founded after studying computer science at the University of Hagen 1994 teuto.net Network Services GmbH in Bielefeld. His focus are new technologies and he is always one of the first to try them out. Developing and operating clouds based on Openstack and Kubernetes are his goal. Burkhard is official corporate sponsor of the OpenStack Foundation, member of Cloud Native Foundation (CNCF) and his company is qualified as a Kubernetes Certified Service Provider.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://devops-gathering.io/speakers/christian-wansart/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://devops-gathering.io/speakers/christian-wansart/</guid>
      <description>Christian Wansart is an Enterprise Developer who works for the open knowledge GmbH. He is a fullstack developer working in backend, frontend and DevOps areas. He uses container technology for years and works with test frameworks to develop stable software with high quality.
 Conference Talk: The Software Factory - Why technology is not enough Halfday-Workshop: Testing with Containers  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://devops-gathering.io/speakers/constantin-weisser/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://devops-gathering.io/speakers/constantin-weisser/</guid>
      <description>Constantin Weisser is a Consultant and Trainer for Novatec Consulting GmbH, based in Germany. He is accompanying customers on their journey to modern software development. He focuses on methods and tools around Software Delivery, i.e. covering all the way from the source code to a running application in the Cloud. Constantin advocates tailored tooling, step-by-step automation and an engineering approaches to speed up software development and delivery, enabling teams to ship high quality applications.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://devops-gathering.io/speakers/dirk-weil/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://devops-gathering.io/speakers/dirk-weil/</guid>
      <description>Dirk Weil has been working as a Java consultant since 1998. As Managing Director of GEDOPLAN GmbH, he is responsible for the conception and realization of Java based information systems. With many years of experience in developing sophisticated business solutions he and his team are competent partners and recognized experts for Java and JEE. He is a book author, writes articles for magazines and speaks at conferences and user groups. He works as trainer for GEDOPLAN IT Training holding various Java and JEE seminars and workshops.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://devops-gathering.io/speakers/ema-rimeike/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://devops-gathering.io/speakers/ema-rimeike/</guid>
      <description> Lighting Talk: Don&amp;rsquo;t Shift Left, START Left  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://devops-gathering.io/speakers/eyal-liebermann/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://devops-gathering.io/speakers/eyal-liebermann/</guid>
      <description>Eyal Liebermann is the Software Architect of SAP Universal ID. An SAP Program that aims to streamline the login and authorization experience across SAP cloud services. Eyal has a unique passion for taking complex legacy systems and transforming them into coherent performant ones. This passion is supported by twenty years of experience, as a developer, a team lead and a software architect, during which he was witnessing grandiose rewrite plans go wary, whereas persistent refactoring efforts seemed to be achieving ambitious goals.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://devops-gathering.io/speakers/florian-kuckelkorn/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://devops-gathering.io/speakers/florian-kuckelkorn/</guid>
      <description>Since 2017 Florian Kuckelkorn is working as a technical coordinator and controller for Protection Technologies (G DATA CyberDefense AG). His primary focus and interest lies on G DATA&amp;rsquo;s Protection Technologies especially on evaluating, tracking and improving backend business processes. Since early age he is technical fascinated and self taught most his knowledge, he has today. He is actively interested in interdisciplinary areas of work and likes the inspiration of dealing with pioneer topics.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://devops-gathering.io/speakers/halil-cem-gursoy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://devops-gathering.io/speakers/halil-cem-gursoy/</guid>
      <description>Halil is a Senior Solution Architect at OPITZ CONSULTING and is already active as Software Developer and Architect since over 20 years. His focus is on large distributed enterprise systems, mostly written in Java, but has wrote more productive infrastructure code in Go, Python or Ruby as classic enterprise Java stuff in the last years.
 Conference Talk: &amp;ldquo;Serverless&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;Functions as a Service&amp;rdquo; with OpenFaaS  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://devops-gathering.io/speakers/kevin-wittek/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://devops-gathering.io/speakers/kevin-wittek/</guid>
      <description>Testcontainers co-maintainer and Testcontainers-Spock author. Software Craftsman and testing fan. Loves to play the electric guitar and is a musician in his second life. Found his own company during his university years, developing mobile apps and client-server applications, which lead to his discovery of Grails and the Groovy ecosystem. Fell in love with TDD because of Spock.
After many years working in the industry as an engineer, Kevin is now doing his PhD at RWTH Aachen on the topic of verification of Smart Contracts and is leading the Blockchain Research Lab at the Institute for Internet Security in Gelsenkirchen at the Westphalian University of Applied Sciences.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://devops-gathering.io/speakers/konstantin-diener/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://devops-gathering.io/speakers/konstantin-diener/</guid>
      <description>Konstantin Diener is CTO at cosee. He has been developing software for more than 15 years. His CTO role made him shift his focus to (agile) leadership topics and how to create a productive environment for self-organised engineering teams. Konstantin speaks at conferences and is author of „DevOps Stories“, a column about culture, leadership, agile and DevOps.
 Conference Talk: The first decade of DevOps is over!   </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://devops-gathering.io/speakers/maggie-otoole/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://devops-gathering.io/speakers/maggie-otoole/</guid>
      <description>Maggie O’Toole is a Solutions Architect for AWS in Germany, and has been with AWS since 2017. She enjoys helping customers improve their business and IT solutions with the AWS Cloud, and specializes in Containers.
 Halfday-Workshop: Amazon EKS Workshop  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://devops-gathering.io/speakers/manuel-zapf/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://devops-gathering.io/speakers/manuel-zapf/</guid>
      <description>Traefik&amp;rsquo;s Solution Architect at Containous. His special interest is in deploying applications scalable by using cloud and container technologies. Gopher lover.
 Conference Talk: Routing Your Microservices Architecture to Ease DevOps Enterprise Transformation  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://devops-gathering.io/speakers/marcel-mueller/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://devops-gathering.io/speakers/marcel-mueller/</guid>
      <description>Marcel is a Platform Engineer at Giant Swarm where he works on Kubernetes Operators and focuses on all things Release Engineering. He is passionate about infrastructure automation in distributed systems and building fault-tolerant software. Marcel is excited to share the learnings he has made along the way. During the last two years he has been closely following Kubernetes upstream developments such as Cluster-API and KIND.
 Halfday Workshop: Introduction to Kubernetes Operators  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://devops-gathering.io/speakers/mario-kleinsasser/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://devops-gathering.io/speakers/mario-kleinsasser/</guid>
      <description>Mario Kleinsasser is the team leader of a small cloud solution operations team within the IT department of the STRABAG SE construction company. Since more than 15 years he&amp;rsquo;s surfing the wave of change with passion. Mario was a speaker at the DevOps Gathering 2018 and 2019 in Bochum Germany, he is the organizer of the Docker South Austria Meetup and he also contributes code for various Open Source projects, like CoreDNS and others.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://devops-gathering.io/speakers/martin-valdes-de-leon/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://devops-gathering.io/speakers/martin-valdes-de-leon/</guid>
      <description>Originally from Argentina, Martin is a Senior Solution Architect with AWS. Prior to joining AWS he worked in various development and architecture roles, specializing in Microservices, Containers and Kubernetes. He now helps enterprise customers expand their businesses with the AWS cloud.
 Halfday-Workshop: Amazon EKS Workshop  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://devops-gathering.io/speakers/matthias-simonis/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://devops-gathering.io/speakers/matthias-simonis/</guid>
      <description>Matthias Simonis works at G DATA since 2016 with a primary focus on the automation of everything. This starts with the setup of infrastructure and ends with the development and deployment of services for automated data processing.
Matthias Simonis is a self taught tech enthusiast that embraces new and old technology to get stuff done.
 Halfday Workshop: Ansible - Testing with Molecule  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://devops-gathering.io/speakers/matthias-wessendorf/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://devops-gathering.io/speakers/matthias-wessendorf/</guid>
      <description>Matthias Wessendorf works on the Messaging team at Red Hat, focusing on event-driven architectures, data-streaming and serverless workloads. He is an active contributor to the Knative project. Matthias is a regular speaker at international conferences and is a long standing member of the Apache Software Foundation.
 Conference Talk: Knative Eventing Deep Dive  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://devops-gathering.io/speakers/niclas-mietz/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://devops-gathering.io/speakers/niclas-mietz/</guid>
      <description>Niclas is a DevOps Engineer, Docker expert and open source maintainer. He accelerates deployment processes in IT projects and systems. With his expertise regarding GitLab/CI pipelines he is an outstanding expert in Continuous Delivery and Continuous Integration.
 Halfday-Workshop: Kubernetes 101  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://devops-gathering.io/speakers/nico-meisenzahl/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://devops-gathering.io/speakers/nico-meisenzahl/</guid>
      <description>Nico Meisenzahl works as Senior Cloud &amp;amp; DevOps Consultant at white duck. As an elected Docker Community Leader and GitLab Hero, his current passion is for topics around Kubernetes, CI/CD, Automation, DevOps, and Cloud.
Nico is a frequent speaker at conferences, user group events and Meetups in Europe and the United States.
 Conference Talk: How Containerized Pipelines Can Boost Your CI/CD  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://devops-gathering.io/speakers/peter-rossbach/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://devops-gathering.io/speakers/peter-rossbach/</guid>
      <description>As Principal Consultant and Director of Software Development at Communicode AG and also System Architect, DevOps Engineer, Apache Member, Apache Tomcat Committer, Infracoder and Docker Influencer, Peter can rely on a long-lasting and remarkable experience. With his skills he inspires not only the communicode, but also our customers to top performances.
 Conference Talk: Cloud Native Ecosystem  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://devops-gathering.io/speakers/philipp-krenn/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://devops-gathering.io/speakers/philipp-krenn/</guid>
      <description>Philipp lives to demo interesting technology. Having worked as a web, infrastructure, and database engineer for over ten years, Philipp is now working as a developer advocate at Elastic — the company behind the Elastic Stack consisting of Elasticsearch, Kibana, Beats, and Logstash.
 Conference Talk: From Containers to Kubernetes Operators  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://devops-gathering.io/speakers/rainer-stropek/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://devops-gathering.io/speakers/rainer-stropek/</guid>
      <description>Rainer Stropek has been an entrepreneur in the IT industry for more than twenty years. During this time, he founded and managed several IT service companies and is currently developing the award-winning Software time cockpit in his company software architects together with his team. Rainer holds degrees from the Technical College of MIS, Leonding (AT) and the University of Derby (UK). He is the author of several books and articles in magazines around Microsoft .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://devops-gathering.io/speakers/robert-douglass/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://devops-gathering.io/speakers/robert-douglass/</guid>
      <description>Robert Douglass has been deeply involved with open source software since 2004. He was the author of the first book published about Drupal, &amp;ldquo;Building Online Communities in Drupal, Wordpress, PhpBB&amp;rdquo; (Apress, 2005), is a core code contributor to 4 different Drupal versions, and the original author of the Memcache and Solr modules for Drupal. Robert has also served as a member of the Drupal Association, a founding member of the German Drupal Association, and a member of the Drupal Security team.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://devops-gathering.io/speakers/roland-huss/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://devops-gathering.io/speakers/roland-huss/</guid>
      <description>Dr. Roland Huß is a principal software engineer at Red Hat and a member of the serverless team for coding on Knative. He has been developing in Java for over twenty years now. However, he has never forgotten his roots as a system administrator. Roland is an active open source contributor, lead developer of the JMX-HTTP bridge Jolokia and some popular Java build tools for creating container images and deploying them on Kubernetes and OpenShift.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://devops-gathering.io/speakers/stephan-mueller/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://devops-gathering.io/speakers/stephan-mueller/</guid>
      <description>Stephan Müller is an Enterprise Architect who works for the open knowledge GmbH. He has worked as an architect, product owner, project manager and coach in numerous enterprise projects for more than a decade. His main interests are architectures, new technologies and clean code.
 Conference Talk: The Software Factory - Why technology is not enough Halfday-Workshop: Testing with Containers  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://devops-gathering.io/speakers/thomas-peitz/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://devops-gathering.io/speakers/thomas-peitz/</guid>
      <description>Thomas Peitz is a Site Reliability Engineer at InVision AG in Düsseldorf. He loves talking about DevOps, infrastructure, containers and serverless, which is why he is also running plenty of meetups around those topics.
 Halfday-Workshop: Going Serverless  </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>