<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Workshops on Devops Gathering 2020 | March 09 - 11, 2020 in Bochum</title>
    <link>https://devops-gathering.io/workshops/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Workshops on Devops Gathering 2020 | March 09 - 11, 2020 in Bochum</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="https://devops-gathering.io/workshops/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Going Serverless</title>
      <link>https://devops-gathering.io/workshops/going-serverless/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://devops-gathering.io/workshops/going-serverless/</guid>
      <description>Everybody&amp;rsquo;s hyped about Serverless, but what is it exactly about and what does it mean to develop a real application with it? Instead of just writing a simple &amp;ldquo;hello world function&amp;rdquo; in this workshop, we&amp;rsquo;re going to create a real weather application using different AWS buildings blocks. While building a scalable and cheap weather application, we&amp;rsquo;ll also look into the tricks and challenges of Lambda, DynamoDB, SQS, XRay and Cloudwatch. At the end of this workshop, you&amp;rsquo;ll have the tools and skills to develop your own Serverless app.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kubernetes 101</title>
      <link>https://devops-gathering.io/workshops/kubernetes-101/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://devops-gathering.io/workshops/kubernetes-101/</guid>
      <description>This Workshop will explain the basic concepts of Kubernetes. Questions like How can I expose my Kubernetes App to the world or How can I run my Container in Kubernetes ? Also it will deliver a Higher Overview over Kubernetes Architecture and the basic components.
Prerequisite knowledge  A working knowledge of the Linux command line A basic understanding of containers and container runtimes like Docker A basic understanding of microservices  What you&amp;rsquo;ll learn During this workshop you will learn the basics components of Kubernetes and get an overview of the current Architecture of Kubernetes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ansible: Testing with Molecule</title>
      <link>https://devops-gathering.io/workshops/ansible-testing-with-molecule/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://devops-gathering.io/workshops/ansible-testing-with-molecule/</guid>
      <description>This workshop gives an introduction on test-driven development of ansible roles with molecule ( https://molecule.readthedocs.io/en/stable )
Molecule provides support for testing with multiple instances, operating systems and distributions, virtualization providers, test frameworks and testing scenarios.
This workshop is hands-on and is designed for molecule beginner, basic ansible knowledge about playbook and role development is required.
Small parts will be implemented in Python, but should be understandable to every developer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introduction to Kubernetes Operators</title>
      <link>https://devops-gathering.io/workshops/introduction-to-kubernetes-operators/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://devops-gathering.io/workshops/introduction-to-kubernetes-operators/</guid>
      <description>Operators are a powerful tool to unlock automation and management potential in clusters. In this workshop I will first introduce and explain some core concepts of Kubernetes operators such as the controller pattern, eventual consistency, custom resources and status management in Kubernetes. The next phase in the workshop will be creating and running your first operator using the Kubebuilder SDK (https://github.com/kubernetes-sigs/kubebuilder) and utilizing KIND (https://github.com/kubernetes-sigs/kind) to deploy your operator locally.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Amazon EKS Workshop</title>
      <link>https://devops-gathering.io/workshops/amazon-eks-workshop/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://devops-gathering.io/workshops/amazon-eks-workshop/</guid>
      <description>Running more than one containerized application in production makes teams look for solutions to quickly deploy and orchestrate containers. One of the most popular options is the open-source project Kubernetes. With the release of the Amazon Elastic Container Service for Kubernetes (EKS), engineering teams now have access to a fully managed Kubernetes control plane and time to focus on building applications. With AWS Fargate, you don’t need to be an expert in Kubernetes operations to run a cost-optimized and highly-available cluster.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to provide reliable Postgres Database inside of Kubernetes Cluster with a Postgres Operator</title>
      <link>https://devops-gathering.io/workshops/reliable-postgres-operator/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://devops-gathering.io/workshops/reliable-postgres-operator/</guid>
      <description>We will show the workings of the Zalando Postgres Operator inside of Kubernetes. We will elaborate on the do and don&amp;rsquo;t of using the Operator. Practical examples how to control Data Placement and Backup will conclude the Workshop. As a bonus we will install an graphile api generator on top of Postgres. graphile automatically generates a graphql api from an Postgres schema and provides a &amp;ldquo;nocode&amp;rdquo; backend for simple Web and Mobile applications.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Testing with Containers</title>
      <link>https://devops-gathering.io/workshops/testing-with-containers/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://devops-gathering.io/workshops/testing-with-containers/</guid>
      <description>Enterprise projects and the resulting challenges are complex by definition. How to master such a system and realize short &amp;ldquo;time-to-market&amp;rdquo; cycles at the same time without negotiating regression errors? The answer is as easy as simple - extensive automated test suites which continuously accumulate the errors back flow. But how to setup these tests when dealing with numerous services, databases, message brokers and other infrastructure to be integrated. At this point Docker comes into the game, which enables us to run an production-near setup in the developer machine as well as in multiple staging environments.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introduction to Go</title>
      <link>https://devops-gathering.io/workshops/introduction-to-go/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://devops-gathering.io/workshops/introduction-to-go/</guid>
      <description>Go has become a popular programming language. Particularly in the DevOps space, Go has risen in popularity because Docker, Kubernetes &amp;amp; Co are written in this programming language. The strengths of Go are beside others simplicity, consistency, good support for async and parallel programming and efficiency. That makes the language a perfect match for Microservices- and DevOps-projects. This workshop is for DevOps engineers who are curious about what Go is. You don&amp;rsquo;t need to have Go experience for this workshop.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>