<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Sponsors on Devops Gathering 2017</title>
    <link>https://devops-gathering.io/sponsors/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in Sponsors on Devops Gathering 2017</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://devops-gathering.io/sponsors/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>9elements</title>
      <link>https://devops-gathering.io/sponsors/9elements/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://devops-gathering.io/sponsors/9elements/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We craft digital products and services.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We combine finest technical craftsmanship with elegant and functional design to ship innovative digital experiences. We have a track record of building successful web and mobile applications for our clients.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Agentur aufgeweckt</title>
      <link>https://devops-gathering.io/sponsors/aufgeweckt/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://devops-gathering.io/sponsors/aufgeweckt/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Trust forms identity - deeply rooted in our location Bochum in the Ruhr area, we are your agency for the digital age. Modern web design and front-end development are our expertise. Trust us and together we shape your identity on the web.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bochum Wirtschaftsentwicklung</title>
      <link>https://devops-gathering.io/sponsors/wifo/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://devops-gathering.io/sponsors/wifo/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We create opportunities and have lots of space, we open doors for you and arrange contacts, we produce ideas, develop concepts and help start-ups. We put our heart and soul into helping you and we’ll never let you down. We at the Bochum Office of Economic Development will support you with our know-how and our passion. Your success is very close to our hearts.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Codencentric AG</title>
      <link>https://devops-gathering.io/sponsors/codecentric/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://devops-gathering.io/sponsors/codecentric/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As an expert in custom software development, codecentric develops software solutions for the future, something every one of our employees at each of our 15 locations is passionate about.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>G Data</title>
      <link>https://devops-gathering.io/sponsors/gdata/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://devops-gathering.io/sponsors/gdata/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;G DATA Software AG, with its head office in Bochum, is an innovative and quickly expanding software house focusing on antivirus security solutions. As a specialist in Internet security and pioneer in the field of virus protection, the company, founded in Bochum in 1985, developed the first antivirus program more than 20 years ago and celebrated its 25th birthday in 2010. Consequently G DATA is amongst the eldest security software companies in the world.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Host1Plus</title>
      <link>https://devops-gathering.io/sponsors/host1plus/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://devops-gathering.io/sponsors/host1plus/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Host1Plus is a global Cloud service delivery platform providing virtualization services in Frankfurt, Chicago, Los Angeles, São Paulo and Johannesburg. Powered by an intuitive UI, on-demand resources and high connectivity around the globe, Host1Plus services are well-built for power users – developers, startups, agencies, big data and business intelligence companies.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Setlog</title>
      <link>https://devops-gathering.io/sponsors/setlog/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://devops-gathering.io/sponsors/setlog/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;At Setlog we like to think value chains holistically – from inbound to outbound. More than a decade ago we&amp;rsquo;ve set out to develop software code that shall be groundbreaking for connective supply chain and vendor management. Our code of conduct? Be distinct, smart, and connective. Expect no less.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our software provides real-time access to crucial information: transparent and coherent. It&amp;rsquo;s universal, uniting each client&amp;rsquo;s global interfaces on one smart connective platform. Bottom line? The single truth about even the most complex value chains. Straightforward and comprehensive.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Styracosoft</title>
      <link>https://devops-gathering.io/sponsors/styracosoft/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://devops-gathering.io/sponsors/styracosoft/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Being Software Craftsmen at heart, we want to help other companies in delivering value by sharing our passion for sofware development and providing consulting, workshops and trainings on topics such as Clean Code, TDD, Continuous Integration, Infrastructure as Code and many more.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>bee42 solutions gmbh</title>
      <link>https://devops-gathering.io/sponsors/bee42/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://devops-gathering.io/sponsors/bee42/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The DevOps company bee42 solutions gmbh in Bochum raises the level of your IT by implementing solutions that perfectly match your requirements. We provide a unique infrastructure solution based on the Docker ecosystem for your needs to build and operate your IT. We love to build infrastructure, implement software, measure systems and are always looking for the next improvement.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>dpunkt.verlag</title>
      <link>https://devops-gathering.io/sponsors/dpunkt/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://devops-gathering.io/sponsors/dpunkt/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Der dpunkt.verlag ist ein modernes Unternehmen im Informationsmarkt. Er bietet Bücher, Zeitschriften und Veranstaltungen für die professionelle Computing-Szene.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fixpunkte des Programms sind Computertechnologie und ihre Anwendungen. dpunkt.bücher wenden sich an Computer-Profis zur Aus- und Fortbildung, ein Schwerpunkt sind Lehrbücher für Studenten an Universitäten und Hochschulen. Eine weitere wichtige Zielgruppe sind professionelle Anwender, für die der Computer das &amp;ldquo;zentrale Werkzeug&amp;rdquo; ihrer Arbeit ist.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>open knowledge</title>
      <link>https://devops-gathering.io/sponsors/open-knowledge/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://devops-gathering.io/sponsors/open-knowledge/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;For more than 15 years OPEN KNOWLEDGE is known for best-in-class consulting, custom software development and coaching in enterprise and mobile computing. We have a strong track record of successfully implemented solutions that are cutting edge whilst being highly maintainable for our national and international customers. Our recipe for success? The perfect mixture of innovation and experience.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>